Guide to the Fred C. Alter papers, 1924-2008 UA 335
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas
Fred C. Alter papers
1924-2008
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas https://library.rice.edu/woodson
Alter, Fred C.
UA 335
1.5 Linear Feet (3 boxes)
The Fred C. Alter papers contain correspondence, memorabilia, Rice notebooks, a personal scrapbook, photographs, and material related to the Robert P. Quin Award.
Biographical / Historical
Fred Cunningham Alter graduated from Rice University in 1934 and was the fourth recipient of the Robert P. Quin Award for excellence in leadership, scholarship, and athletics. Born in San Antonio, Texas, on October 8, 1913, he excelled from a young age in tennis and academics, winning the San Antonio Junior Tennis Tournament singles competition and acting as president of his senior high school class.
After graduating from Rice University, Alter earned his L.L.B. from the South Texas School of Law in 1941. He went on to serve in the U.S. Army from 1943-1946, supervising Japanese P.O.W. camps in New Caledonia, Guadalcanal, and Manila. Discharged at the rank of captain, he returned to Texas to work at Matteson-Southwest Advertising Company until 1949 when he assumed a management position at Wetmore & Company. In 1960, he became president of the Trans-State Outdoor Advertising Company until his retirement in 1985. He was a trustee for South Texas Junior College and was an active member of the Vestry of Christ Church Cathedral since 1949. He presented the Robert P. Quin award on numerous occasions before his death on March 20, 2002.
Scope and Contents
The Fred C. Alter papers contain correspondence, memorabilia, Rice notebooks, a personal scrapbook, photographs, and material related to the Robert P. Quin Award. Alter was a Rice Institute almunus and World War II veteran.
Access Restrictions
This material is open for research. Stored off-site at the Library Service Center. Please request this material via woodson@rice.edu or call 713-348-2586.
Acquisition
This collection was donated by Stephen G. Alter in 2013.
Index Terms
Subjects
Universities and colleges; College students -- Texas; World War (1939-1945); Sports
Document Types
memorabilia; photographs; scrapbooks; military records; awards; notes
- Series I: Rice Related, 1924-2008; 172090
  - Scrapbook, 1924-1931; 172091 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Campus-related Photographs, 1932-1934; 172092 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Robert P. Quin Award, 1934-2008; 172093 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - English 100/200, 1930-1931; 172094 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - American History 300, Fall 1932; 172095 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - English 420, Volume 1, Fall 1932; 172096 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - English 420, Volume 2, 1933; 172103 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Economics 330, 1933-1934; 172104 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Philosophy 300, Volume I, 1933; 172097 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Philosophy 300, Volume 2, 1934; 172098 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Philosophy 300, Volume 3, 1934; 172100 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Unspecified Class Notes 1, 1934; 172101 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Unspecified Class Notes 2, 1934; 172102 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Slime Helmet, 1930; 172107 (Box 3)
- Series II: Career & World War II, 1941-2002; 172109
  - Post-Rice Career, 1941-1949; 172221 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - World War II Service, 1941-1946; 172222 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Obituary, 2002; 172223 (Box 2, Folder 10)